A true story based on interview transcripts and records
Detainment is a drama, crime, documentary film directed by Vincent Lambe.
Two ten year-old boys are detained by police under
suspicion of abducting and murdering a toddler.
Jon, played by Ely Solan.
Robert, played by Leon Hughes.
Detective Dale, played by Will O'Connell.
Detective Scott, played by David Ryan.
Susan Venables, played by Tara Breathnach.
Detective Roberts, played by Morgan C. Jones.
Detainment is a 2018 Irish short drama film written and directed by
Vincent Lambe, about the murder of James Bulger.
It was nominated for the Best Live Action Short Film at the 91st Academy Awards.
The film explores themes of child abuse, kidnapping, based on
true story, murder, criminal investigation.
The tone is emotional.